PARVEEN KUMAR

H-110/15

Vill-Chaura Sec-22

Noida –G.B Nagar UP- 201301

MOB.: +91 9818799101

EMAIL ID: parveenkumar232@gmail.com



Brief Profile

To get a responsible and professionally challenging position, where I can make Contribution of my knowledge & skills for the growth and development of the organization.

A professional with 5 years of experience in sales, customer relationship management & back office operations

Professional Qualification

MBA (Marketing & HR) from (G. B. Technical University, Lucknow in 2011)

Career Highlights

Company: Self Employed

Delhi Ncr

Profile : Management

DURATION: Sep 2014 Till date....

Company: Serai Shipping Services

Dubai, UAE.

Profile: Operations Executive **DURATION:** Feb 2012 to July 2014.

Areas of Exposure:-

Customer Relationship Management:

- Building and maintaining healthy business relationships with corporate clients, ensuring customer satisfaction by achieving delivery & service quality norms.
- Supervising customer service operations for rendering and achieving quality services, facilitating first line customer support by answering quarries & resolving issues.
- An effective communicator with excellent relationship building & interpersonal skills, strong analytical, problem solving & organizational abilities.

Back Office Operations:-

- Ensure effective liaison with agents and coordinated arrangement of shipments.
- Comprehensive understanding of export and import documentation be able to issue documents that comply with the shipping declaration requirements.
- Negotiate with Forwarder to the lowest best price with comprehensive payment terms.
- Approve bookings for container and freight pick up, and ensure coordination for shipments.
- Take responsibility for the shipment from its origin country until the shipment is delivered to the Warehouse.
- Review and sign off shipping documents while ensuring completeness and accuracy.
- Assist to prepare Authorization letter and send to forwarder together with shipping documents for clearance of the goods from the port.
- Seek innovative ways to improve service and cost, which will include both technological and process improvements.
- Ensure compliance with import/export regulations for all equipment and materials.
- Review and approve and follow up the documents, processes and controls of freight payment and audit system and ensure all documents, processes and controls are updated.

- Support the supply chain process through planning, on line allocation, pick release and invoicing to ensure customer's requirements are met.
- Manage archiving of completed shipment files and maintain record keeping.

Past Company: VIDEOCOND2H

DESIGNATION: Operation Executive, Delhi NCR, India.

DURATION: 22-Jan 2011 to 19 -Nov 2011.

Brief of Job:

- Valuable experience in customer support and services in the sales and marketing sectors.
- Developed a good customer relationship of both existing and building new clients.
- Continually engaged in building clear and complete knowledge of products, workflow and procedures to enhance the quality of services.
- Assisted the sales functions in locating and introducing new corporate clients.
- Ensured timely processing of products and delivery to clients.
- Providing products information to customers.
- Attending to customers gueries & complains.

Academic Credentials

MBA (Marketing & HR) from G.B. Tech. University, Lucknow, India) in 2011.

Bachelor Degree in Arts from V.V.S University U.P/ (India) in 2008.

XII from U.P. Board (V.M.K. Inter College, Allahabad) (Science Stream) in 2004.

X from U.P. Board (V.M.K. Inter College, Allahabad) (Science Stream) in 2001.

Technical Skills

Diploma In Computer Hardware Maintenance 'O' Level In Doeacc Society.

Diploma In Computer Application (DCA)

Operating System : Window xp Window Vista

Spreadsheet : MS- excel

Presentation : MS- PowerPoint

Word processor : MS- word

Internet operations : Internet Explorer, Net Surfing, MS Outlook

Strong Traits

Ability to quickly learn and implement

Patience & cooperation in team

People management skills

Always willing to learn new things

Multi-tasking.

Personal Details

Date of birth : July 1st 1986

Father's name : Mr. Laxmi Shanker Mother's name : Smt. Gayatri devi

Permanent add : Vill. Kishora, Post Handia,

: Dist-Allahabad, U.P. India-221503

Passport No. : H0764700 Language Known : English, Hindi

References on Request

I hereby solemnly declare that the above particulars are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Noida

Date : (Parveen Kumar)